## Joe Rogers

Site Reliability Engineer Manager | AI Champion | Infrastructure Optimization 310.903.8312 | joe@joe-r.net | linkedin:go2joerogers | Torrance, CA

#### Summary

Over 20 years of digital transformation and optimization experience in SRE and DevOps, from Solaris and data centers to containers and Al. Currently leading Al transformation efforts and infrastructure modernization using GitLab Cl, ECS, and Bedrock. Six years leading teams, scaling platforms, and leveraging automation to drive efficiency and uptime. with an IaC first mindset.

#### **Skills**

Mentoring, Training, Motivating, EKS, Kubernetes, ECS, Fargate, Docker, IAM, VPC, Route 53, Bedrock, VSCode, Python, Bash, Copilot, Cloudflare, Datadog, Splunk, Terraform, Ansible Loves: Gemini, Claude, Perplexity, DeepSeek, Cline, Windsurf, OpenAI

## **Experience**

**Core Digital Media** 

Playa Vista, CA

Site Reliability Engineer Manager

July 2021 - Present

- Led containerization project to modernize 50+ apps from EC2 to ECS
- Created internal Infrastructure LLM Slack Bot, championed AI code assistant tools, LLM adoption
- Instilled a mindset of Infrastructure as Code first principals, deploying infra that is repeatable, accountable, and managed via a single source of truth
- Migrated CI/CD from AWS Code Pipeline to GitLab CI, shifting left on testing, and cutting new app creation from two weeks to two days, and release lead time from one day to one hour.

Core Digital Media
Principal System Administrator

Playa Vista, CA Jan 2019 - July 2021

- Migrated 500+ datacenter hosted VMWare VMs to AWS EC2
- Dramatically reduced our AWS costs
- Greatly increased code deployment from once a week to once a day by migrating from Jenkins to AWS Code Pipeline / Code Build / Code Deploy

#### Lowermybills Senior System Engineer

Playa Vista, CA Jan 2013 - Dec 2018

- Complete data center migration from one colo to another (again)
- Migration to VMWare and 1000+ VMs
- Automation, Ansible, Puppet and Puppet

# Experian Interactive Media Senior System Engineer

Culver City, CA Dec 2008 – Jan 2013

- Maintained 100% uptime during a 300-server datacenter migration
- Deployed Red Hat Satellite patching across 300 servers and instituted a monthly staged patching cycle across Dev → QA → Stage → Prod
- Consolidated DNS infrastructure to BIND 9 (primary/secondary) with zero downtime; migrated back office DNS from Microsoft AD to BIND
- Implemented VMWare with ten ESX hosts to deliver scalable Stage/QA/DEV/ENG environments, leveraging P2V, cloning, LVM, and templates

### **Education**

**UCLA**, Los Angeles

**Electrical Engineering**